The Cornwall Pumped Storage Project Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Cornwall Pumped Storage Project Collection
1953 - 1981
NPkMC-222-091
7 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference
The Cornwall Collection documents the issues surrounding the Pumped-Storage Project at Cornwall-on-Hudson by the Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. The collection includes various scientific studies in the Hudson River Estuary, specifically fish studies in the Indian Point area. It also includes legal documents from the Storm King Case, correspondence, and newspaper clippings.
Related Collections
Alexander Saunders Papers: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1962 - 1966
Grim Collection: Hudson River Fisheries Investigation, 1965 - 1968
Hudson River Environmental Society Collection, 1963 - 2005
Hudson River Valley Greenway Council Collection, 1989-1996
Hudson Valley GREEN Collection, 1981 - 2002
Mr. and Mrs. Henry Dain Papers, 1963 - 1967
On the River Collection, 1986 - 1993
Scenic Hudson, Inc. Administrative History Collection, 1960- 2000
Scenic Hudson Decision Hearings Transcripts Collection, 1977- 1980
Senator Mrs. Whitney N. Seymour Jr. Papers: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1962-1978
Collection Overview
The Cornwall Collection contains a variety of scientific studies, including ecological studies of the Hudson River Estuary, fisheries investigations, and the impact of the power plant on the fish and environment. In addition, the collection has several newspaper clippings related to the Storm King Case and Indian Point.
Acquisitions Information
The Cornwall Pumped Storage Project Collection was donated to Marist College by the Cornwall Public Library.
Historical Note
In September 1962, the Consolidated Edison Company announced plans to build a pumped storage facility, the largest of its kind in the world, at Storm King Mountain near Cornwall, New York. The initial application for license to construct the plant was filed with the Federal Power Commission in January 1963. On November 8, 1963, a small group of concerned citizens met at the home of Carl Carmer and formed the Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference to fight the pumped storage project on the grounds that it posed a threat to the Cornwall water supply, the Hudson River fisheries, and to the scenic beauty and historic significance of Storm King Mountain. Thanks to the tireless work of those involved with Scenic Hudson, the mountain would come to weather this storm as well. Today the mountain is home to Storm King State Park and thousands of visitors come to hike the trails this historic mountain has to offer.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
- 1. Reports, 1966 - 1979; 1; 5 Linear Feet Boxes: 1 - 5
  Series contains scientific studies pertaining to the influence of the power plant on the ecosystem of the Hudson River.
  By subject, chronological
  - Subseries 1.1: Hudson River Ecological Studies, 1973 - 1978; 1.1; Box: 1 - 2
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, April 1973 (Folder 1, Box 1)
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, Nov. 1973 (Folder 2, Box 1)
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, 1973 Annual Report (Folder 3, Box 1)
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, 1974 Annual Report (Folder 4, Box 1)
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, 1975 Annual Report (Folder 5, Box 1)
    - Semi-Annual Progress Report for Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, April 1975 (Folder 6, Box 1)
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, 1976 Annual Report (Folder 1, Box 2)
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point - Thermal Effects Report, Sept. 1976 (Folder 2, Box 2)
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, 1977 Annual Report (Folder 3, Box 2)
    - Hudson River Ecological Study: in the area of Indian Point, 1978 Annual Report (Folder 4, Box 2)
  - Subseries 1.2: Hudson River Ecosystems Studies, 1971 - 1975; 1.2; Box: 3 - 4
    - Hudson River Ecosystem Studies: Effects of Entrainment by the Indian Point Power Plant on Biota in the Hudson River Estuary, Progress Report for 1971 and 1972 (Folder 1, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Ecosystem Studies: Effects of Entrainment by the Indian Point Power Plant on Biota in the Hudson River Estuary, Addenda to: the 1973 Report (Folder 2, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Ecosystem Studies: Effects of Entrainment by the Indian Point Power Plant on Biota in the Hudson River Estuary, Progress Report for 1973 (Folder 3, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Ecosystem Studies: Semi-Annual Progress Report, 1 January to 10 June, 1974 (Folder 4, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Ecosystem Studies: Effects of Entrainment by the Indian Point Power Plant on Biota in the Hudson River Estuary, Progress Report for 1974 (Folder 5, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Ecosystem Studies: Effects of Temperature and Chlorine on Entrained Hudson River Organisms, Progress Report for 1975 (Folder 6, Box 3)
    - Hudson River Ecosystem Studies: Effects of Entrainment by the Indian Point Power Plant on Biota in the Hudson River Estuary, Progress Report for 1975 (Folder 1, Box 4)
    - Hudson River Ecosystem Studies: Effects of Entrainment by the Indian Point Power Plant on Biota in the Hudson River Estuary, Progress Report for 1976 (Folder 2, Box 4)
  - Subseries 1.3: Multi-Plant Impact Study, 1975 - 1979; 1.3; Box: 4 - 6
    - 1974 Year-Class Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary, Volume 1 Text, May 1977 (Folder 3, Box 4)
    - 1974 Year-Class Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary, Volume 2 Appendices, May 1977 (Folder 4, Box 4)
    - 1974 Year-Class Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary, Volume 3 Lower Estuary Study, May 1977 (Folder 5, Box 4)
    - 1975 Year-Class Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary, June 1978 Final Report (Folder 6, Box 4)
    - Semi-Annual Progress Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary, Feb. 1975 (Folder 1, Box 5)
    - First Annual Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary, Volume 1 Text, July 1975 (Folder 2, Box 5)
    - First Annual Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary, Volume 2 Appendices, July 1975 (Folder 3, Box 5)
    - 1976 Year-Class Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary, May 1979 (Folder 4, Box 5)
    - 1977 Year-Class Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary (Folder 1, Box 6)
    - 1978 Year-Class Report for the Multi-Plant Impact Study of the Hudson River Estuary (no folder) (Folder 2, Box 6)
  - Subseries 1.4: Indian Point Studies, 1972 - 1977; 1.4; Box: 7 - 10
    - Indian Point Flume Study: First Progress Report, Aug. 1975 (Folder 1, Box 7)
    - Indian Point Flume Study: Final Report, July 1976 (Folder 2, Box 7)
    - Indian Point Generating Station a 316(a) Demonstration (Folder 3, Box 7)
    - Indian Point Generating Station a 316(a) Demonstration, Appendix D: Procedures and Analyses - Biological and Hydrothermal Studies (Folder 4, Box 7)
    - Indian Point Generating Station Entrainment Survival and Related Studies, 1977 Annual Report (Folder 5, Box 7)
    - Indian Point Generating Station Entrainment Survival and Related Studies, 1978 Annual Report (Folder 1, Box 8)
    - Indian Point Generating Plants: A Hydraulic Model Study of Hudson River Flows around Cooling Water Intakes, Nov. 1976 (Folder 2, Box 8)
    - Indian Point Impingement Study Report for the Period 15 June 1972 through 31 December 1973 (Folder 3, Box 8)
    - Indian Point Impingement Study Report for the Period 1 January 1974 through 31 December 1974 (Folder 4, Box 8)
    - Indian Point Impingement Study Report for the Period 1 January 1975 through 31 December 1975 (Folder 5, Box 8)
    - Indian Point Unit No. 2&3 - Near-Field Effects of Once-Through Cooling System Operation on Hudson River Biota, Appendices 1.1 and 1.2, July 1977 (Folder 6, Box 8)
    - Indian Point Unit No. 2&3 - Near-Field Effects of Once-Through Cooling System Operation on Hudson River Biota, July 1977 (Folder 1, Box 9)
    - Influence of Indian Point Unit 2 and Other Steam Electric Generating Plants on the Hudson River Estuary, with Emphasis on Striped Bass and Other Fish: Supplement 1, July 1977 (Folder 2, Box 9)
    - Influence of Indian Point Unit 2 and Other Steam Electric Generating Plants on the Hudson River Estuary, with Emphasis on Striped Bass and Other Fish Population, Jan. 1977 (no folder) (Folder 1, Box 10)
    - Errata for: “Supplement 1 to Influence of Indian Point Unit 2 and Other Steam Electric Generating Plants on the Hudson River Estuary, with Emphasis on Striped Bass and Other Fish Population” (Folder 2, Box 10)
  - Subseries 1.5: Culturing and Stocking Striped Bass Studies, 1973 - 1975; 1.5; Box: 11 - 13
    - Feasibility of Culturing and Stocking Hudson River Striped Bass: An Overview, 1973-1975 (Folder 1, Box 11)
    - Feasibility of Culturing and Stocking Hudson River Striped Bass, July 1974 (Folder 2, Box 11)
    - Second Semi-Annual Report Related to the Feasibility Study for Spawning, Hatching and Stocking Striped Bass in the Hudson River, Nov. 1974 (Folder 3, Box 11)
    - Feasibility of Culturing and Stocking Hudson River Striped Bass, 1974 Annual Report (Folder 4, Box 11)
    - Feasibility of Culturing and Stocking Hudson River Striped Bass, 1975 Annual Report (Folder 5, Box 11)
  - Subseries 1.6: Fish and Fisheries Studies, 1975 - 1978; 1.6; Box: 11 - 12
    - Catch Efficiency of 100-ft Beach Seins for Estimating Density of young-of-the-year Striped Bass and White Perch... June 1978 Final Report (Folder 6, Box 11)
    - Cytogenetic Study of the Striped Bass from the Hudson River, Sept. 1976 (Folder 7, Box 11)
    - The Effects of Changes in Hydrostatic Pressure on some Hudson River Biota Progress Report 1974 (Folder 8, Box 11)
    - The Effects of changes in Hydrostatic Pressure on some Hudson River Biota Progress Report 1975 (Folder 9, Box 11)
    - Efficiency of the 1.0m^2 Epibenthic Sled... 1978 (Folder 10, Box 11)
    - Efficiency of a 100-ft Beach Seine for Estimating Shore Zone Densities at night of... Striped Bass and... White Perch July 1979 (Folder 11, Box 11)
    - Evaluation of a Submerged Weir to Reduce Fish Impingment... 25 May - 29 July, 1977 (Folder 12, Box 11)
    - Feasibility Study and Design Development Striped Bass Fish Hatchery... Dec. 15, 1974 (Folder 1, Box 12)
    - Final Report of the Synoptic Subpopulation Analysis. Phase 1, Sept, 1975 (Folder 2, Box 12)
    - First Annual Progress Report on Fisheries Investigations - Cornwall, NY May 1974 (Folder 3, Box 12)
    - Hudson River Program Fisheries Data Summary, Vol. 1, Oct. 1973 (Folder 4, Box 12)
    - Hudson River Program Fisheries Data Summary, Vol. 2 Dec. 1973 (Folder 5, Box 12)
    - Fisheries Survey of the Hudson River Vol. 3, March 1974 (Folder 6, Box 12)
    - Fisheries Survey of the Hudson River Vol. 4 Revised Edition. June 1976 (Folder 1, Box 13)
    - Influence of the Proposed Cornwall Pumped Storage Project and Steam Electric Generating Plants on the Hudson River Estuary with Emphasis on Striped Bass and Other Fish Populations (Folder 2, Box 13)
    - Influence of the Proposed Cornwall Pumped Storage Project and Steam Electric Generating Plants on the Hudson River Estuary with Emphasis on Striped Bass and Other Fish Populations - Revised July 1978 (no ) (Folder 1, Box 14)
    - Initial and Extended Survival or Fish... at the Indian Point Generating Station 15 June - 22 Dec., 1977 (Folder 2, Box 14)
    - Life Stage Duration Studies on Hudson River Striped Bass - Final Report, Sept. 1974 (Folder 3, Box 14)
    - Mortality of Striped Bass Eggs and Larvac in Nets, July 1976 (Folder 4, Box 14)
    - Predation by Bluefish in the Lower Hudson River Feb. 1976 (Folder 5, Box 14)
    - A Preliminary Evaluation of the Potential Impact on the Fisheries... Sept. 1975 (Folder 1, Box 15)
    - Production of Striped Bass for Experimental Purposes 1976 Hatchery Report (Folder 2, Box 15)
    - Production of striped Bass for Power Plant Entrainment Studies 1977 Hatchery Report (Folder 3, Box 15)
    - Racial Investigation of the Striped Bass Using Critical Scale Analysis Final Report 1975 (Folder 4, Box 15)
    - The Rearing of Hudson River Striped Bass at the Edenton National Fish Hatchery, 1975 (Folder 5, Box 15)
    - Report on 1978-1979 Studies to Evaluate Catch Efficiency of the 1.0m^2 Epibenthic Sled Sept. 1980 (Folder 6, Box 15)
    - Report on Development of a Real-Time, Two Dimensional Model of the Hudson River Striped Bass Population Oct. 1975 (Folder 7, Box 15)
    - Report on Relative Contribution of Hudson River Striped Bass to the Atlantic Coastal Fishery, Dec. 1976 (Folder 8, Box 15)
    - Striped Bass Rearing Experiments 1975 (Folder 9, Box 15)
    - Striped Bass Rearing Experiments 1976 (Folder 10, Box 15)
  - Subseries 1.7: Other Scientific Studies, 1966 - 1979; 1.7; Box: 15
    - 1975 Cornwall Transect Data Display, Aug. 1976 (Folder 11, Box 15)
    - Acute and Chronic Effects of Evaporative Cooling Tower Blowdown and Power Plant Chemical Discharges on White Perch and Striped Bass, Nov. 1974 (Folder 12, Box 15)
    - Benthic Landfill Studies: Cornwall, Final Report, Feb. 1975 (Folder 13, Box 15)
    - Cornwall Pumped Storage Scheme: Hydraulic Model Study of Hudson River Flows Around Screen Structure, July 1976 (Folder 14, Box 15)
    - The Effects of Intakes and Associated Cooling Water Systems on Phythoplankton and Aquatic Invertebrates of the Hudson River, July 1977 (Folder 1, Box 16)
    - Evaluation of the Effectiveness of a Continuously Operating Fine Mesh Traveling Screen for Reducing Ichthyoplankton Entrainment at the Indian Point Generating Station, April 1979 (Folder 2, Box 16)
    - Gear Evaluation Studies 1974 and 1975 (Folder 3, Box 16)
    - Hudson River Environmental Study: in the area of Ossining, Final Report, Jan. 1975 (Folder 4, Box 16)
    - Hudson River Model Study in the Area of the Cornwall Pumped Storage Project by Alden Research Laboratories, Feb. - Aug., 1966 (Folder 5, Box 16)
    - Hudson River Thermal Effects Studies for Representative Species: Final Report, March 1978 (Folder 6, Box 16)
    - Preliminary Investigations into the Use of a Continuously Operating Fine Mesh Traveling Screen to Reduce Ichthyoplankton Entrainment at Indian Point Generating Station, Dec. 1977 (Folder 7, Box 16)
    - Survival of Entrained Ichthyoplankton and Macroinvertebrates at Hudson River Power Plants, July 1977 (Folder 8, Box 16)
    - A Synthesis of Available Data Pertaining to Major Physicochemical Variables within the Hudson River Estuary, Nov. 1976 (Folder 9, Box 16)
    - Thermal Effects Literature Review for Hudson River Representative Important Species, March 1978 (Folder 10, Box 16)
- 2. Clippings, 1953 - 1966; 2; 1 Linear Foot Box: 17 - 19
  Series contains newspaper and magazine clippings concerning the issues surrounding Storm King and Indian Point from 1953 to 1966.
  Chronological
  - Clippings - 1953 (Folder 1, Box 17)
  - Clippings - 1954 (Folder 2, Box 17)
  - Clippings - 1955 (Folder 3, Box 17)
  - Clippings - 1956 (Folder 4, Box 17)
  - Clippings - 1957 (Folder 5, Box 17)
  - Clippings - 1958 (Folder 6, Box 17)
  - Clippings - 1959 (Folder 7, Box 17)
  - Clippings - 1960 (Folder 8, Box 17)
  - Clippings - 1962 (Folder 9, Box 17)
  - Clippings - Jan.-March, 1963 (Folder 10, Box 17)
  - Clippings - April-Aug., 1963 (Folder 11, Box 17)
  - Clippings - Sept.-Dec., 1963 (Folder 12, Box 17)
  - Clippings - Jan.-March, 1964 (Folder 1, Box 18)
  - Clippings - April-June, 1964 (Folder 2, Box 18)
  - Clippings - Aug.-Dec., 1964 (Folder 3, Box 18)
  - Clippings - Jan.-Feb., 1965 (Folder 4, Box 18)
  - Clippings - March-April, 1965 (Folder 5, Box 18)
  - Clippings - May-July, 1965 (Folder 1, Box 19)
  - Clippings - Aug.-Dec., 1965 (Folder 2, Box 19)
  - Clippings - Jan.-Feb., 1966 (Folder 3, Box 19)
  - Clippings - March-Sept., 1966 (Folder 4, Box 19)
  - Clippings - Sept.-Dec., 1966 (Folder 5, Box 19)
  - Clippings - No Date (Folder 6, Box 19)
- 3. Legal Documents, 1964 - 1968; 3; 0.5 Linear Feet Box: 19 - 20
  Series contains briefs, testimony, and exhibits concerning the Storm King Case.
  By subject
  - Subseries 3.1: Briefs, 1964 - 1968; 3.1; Box: 19 - 20
    - Brief of Applicant, Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., Opposing Exceptions to the Examiner’s Initial Decision, Oct. 7, 1964 (Folder 7, Box 19)
    - Reply Brief of the Town of Cornwall, Feb. 24, 1966 (Folder 8, Box 19)
    - Village of Cornwall Brief After Hearing in the Support of the Application of Consolidated Edison Company Docket No. P-2338, July 30, 1967 (Folder 9, Box 19)
    - Brief of Applicant Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., After Further Hearings on Remand, August 14, 1967 (Folder 10, Box 19)
    - Brief on Behalf of Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, Intervenor: Volume 1, Aug. 14, 1967 (Folder 11, Box 19)
    - Brief on Behalf of Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, Intervenor: Volume 2 (Folder 1, Box 20)
    - Commission Staff Brief - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., Aug. 14, 1967 (Folder 2, Box 20)
    - Reply Brief of Applicant Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., After Further Hearings on Remand, September 5, 1967 (Folder 3, Box 20)
    - Brief on Exceptions for Applicant Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., October 7, 1968 (Folder 4, Box 20)
    - Brief Opposing Exceptions for Applicant, Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., October 24, 1968 (Folder 5, Box 20)
  - Subseries 3.2: Exhibits, 3.2; Box: 20
    - Callison Exhibit 1A-1I: Photographs of Storm King and Hudson River - Related to Site of Pumped Storage Project in Cornwall (Folder 6, Box 20)
    - Eliot Exhibits #1-5: Photographs of Storm King and Hudson River - Related to Site of Pumped Storage Project in Cornwall (Folder 7, Box 20)
    - Exhibits Accompanying Testimony of Staff Witness Joseph J. A. Jessel - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., October, 1966 (Folder 8, Box 20)
    - Duncan Exhibits 1-2: Proposed Transmission Line Route Project Powerhouse to Millwood (Folder 9, Box 20)
    - Mullarkey Exhibit #1-4: General Map (site), Site Plans, Cross Sections, Plan-Operating Floor, Tunnels&Intake Section, Dike Section (Folder 10, Box 20)
    - Rutledge Exhibit #1-3: Cornwall Pumped Storage Project: Drawings 11, 12, 13, Stability Analysis of Dike 1 (Folder 11, Box 20)
    - Shew Exhibit 1: Various Alternative Underground Routes Considered (Folder 12, Box 20)
  - Subseries 3.3: Other Legal Documents, 3.3; Box: 20
    - Agreement: Land Upper Res., Oct. 13, 1964 (Folder 13, Box 20)
    - Agreement: Increased Cost of Operation, Oct. 13, 1964 (Folder 14, Box 20)
    - Agreement: Sale of Land, Oct. 13, 1964 (Folder 15, Box 20)
    - Certificate of Service - Brief Opposing Exceptions, Oct. 7, 1964 (Folder 16, Box 20)
    - Direct Testimony: Fred C. Stein (Folder 17, Box 20)
    - Prepared Rebuttal Testimony of Mr. M. L. Wong (opposition), including Photos (Folder 18, Box 20)
- 4. Office Materials, 1965 - 1980; 4; 0.5 Linear Feet Box: 21 - 22
  Series contains correspondence, pamphlets, research materials, and office materials
  - Subseries 4.1: Correspondence, 4.1; Box: 21
    - Correspondence 1963 (Folder 1, Box 21)
    - Correspondence 1965 (Folder 2, Box 21)
    - Correspondence 1966 (Folder 3, Box 21)
    - Correspondence Not Dated (Folder 4, Box 21)
    - Memorandum (Folder 5, Box 21)
  - Subseries 4.2: Pamphlets and Publications, 1965 - 1980; 4.2; Box: 21 - 22
    - Activities of the Botanical Institutes at Harvard, 1965-1966 (Folder 6, Box 21)
    - Air Pollution: The Facts (Folder 7, Box 21)
    - Be a Pollution Detective (Folder 8, Box 21)
    - Black Rock Forest Papers: The Issues in the Storm King Controversy (Folder 9, Box 21)
    - Black Rock Forest Papers: The Price of Open Space - The Need for Research (Folder 10, Box 21)
    - Black Rock Forest Papers: Recreation Use within the Harvard Black Rock Forest (Folder 11, Box 21)
    - Can You Talk to Language of the Astrospace Age? (Folder 12, Box 21)
    - Con Edison: Cornwall (Folder 13, Box 21)
    - The Cornwall Hydroelectric Project: Power and Beauty for Tomorrow (Folder 14, Box 21)
    - The Cornwall Local - Dec. 16, 1981&Dec. 24, 1980 Re: Pump Storage Project (Folder 15, Box 21)
    - Cornwall News&Views: A Con Edison Public Information Service, March 18, 1966 (Folder 16, Box 21)
    - Cornwall Pumped-Storage Project: Answers to Question Frequently Asked (Folder 17, Box 21)
    - Danger for Sportsmen, Hunters&Gunners, Fishermen, Boatmen, and Conservationists (Folder 18, Box 21)
    - Decision on the Hudson (Folder 19, Box 21)
    - Electric Energy and the Environment (Folder 20, Box 21)
    - The Empire State Mason, Jan.-Feb., 1965 (Folder 21, Box 21)
    - Fish and Power Plants (Folder 22, Box 21)
    - Focus on the Hudson: Evaluation and Proposals of Alternatives (Folder 23, Box 21)
    - The Great Battle for Storm King (Folder 24, Box 21)
    - Harper’s: “Environmentalism and the Leisure Class” Dec. 1977 (Folder 25, Box 21)
    - The Hudson: Summary Report of the Hudson River Valley Commission (Folder 26, Box 21)
    - Invest in Conservation - Sportsmen’s Council (Folder 27, Box 21)
    - Jersey Angler’s News (Folder 28, Box 21)
    - Library Service to the People of New York State (Folder 29, Box 21)
    - New York’s Pure Water Progress ‘69 (Folder 30, Box 21)
    - News and Views for Stockholders (Folder 31, Box 21)
    - Office for Local Government Newsletter, Jan. 17, 1966 (Folder 32, Box 21)
    - Power for Tomorrow (Folder 33, Box 21)
    - The Preservation of Storm King Mountain - Information Kit (Folder 34, Box 21)
    - Preserving Our Heritage (Folder 35, Box 21)
    - Quarterly Bulletin for Common Stockholders (Folder 36, Box 21)
    - Recreation Proposal: Cornwall Pumped-Storage Project (Folder 37, Box 21)
    - Restoration and Power: Creative Conservation at Cornwall-on-Hudson (Folder 38, Box 21)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference Bulletin #17, July 17, 1966 (Folder 39, Box 21)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference Bulletin #18, Aug. 15, 1966 (Folder 40, Box 21)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference Bulletin #19, Sept. 20, 196 (Folder 41, Box 21)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference Capsule Report, Oct. 11, 1966 (Folder 42, Box 21)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference: “Con Edison Must Not Build at Storm King, They Can be Stopped” (Folder 43, Box 21)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference: “Position Report” (Folder 44, Box 21)
    - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference Newsletter, Dec. 29, 1965 (Folder 45, Box 21)
    - “A Stink of Dead Stripers” (Folder 46, Box 21)
    - To the Voters, Village of Cornwall Notice of Annual Election 1966 (Folder 47, Box 21)
    - The Truth vs. Twenty Unfounded Charges (Folder 1, Box 22)
    - Welcome to Deerfield Valley Station (Folder 2, Box 22)
  - Subseries 4.3: Research Materials, 4.3; Box: 22
    - Application of Con Edison’s Certificate of Reasonable Assurance, Cornwall Project, March 18, 1971 (Folder 3, Box 22)
    - Bibliography - Hudson River (Re: Con Edison Pump Storage Project) (Folder 4, Box 22)
    - Comment Regarding Hazer&Sawer Report (Folder 5, Box 22)
    - Con Edison’s Proposed Hydroelectric Project, Cornwall, New York (Folder 6, Box 22)
    - Groups and Organizations in Support of the Cornwall Project, Collected by Con Edison, June 1966 (Folder 7, Box 22)
    - Hudson River Ecology: Second Symposium, Oct. 1969 (Folder 8, Box 22)